<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Anqi Zhang Blog</title>
        <link>https://anqi-j.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Anqi Zhang Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in Christianity]]></title>
            <link>https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion</link>
            <guid>https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As a worldview, Christianity presents its own unique Diversity-Equity-Inclusion statement to the world. Let us hear and act.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2>
<p>Recently, I have been learning how to draft a diversity-equity-inclusion (DEI) statement. I came to realize that these concepts are not a novel modern awakening, but are long seeded in the hearts of whoever has a sense of conscience and morality and well thought through in Christianity.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="christianity-teaches-the-source-and-value-of-diversity">Christianity Teaches the Source and Value of Diversity<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#christianity-teaches-the-source-and-value-of-diversity" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Christianity Teaches the Source and Value of Diversity" title="Direct link to Christianity Teaches the Source and Value of Diversity">​</a></h2>
<p>God is diverse in His nature. His infinite beauty and glory raises up from His infinite complexity and understanding. Christianity observes a triune God. The Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit are the three relational projections of God based on the revelation of God and the experience of men.</p>
<p>Overflowing His diversity, God spoke into existence all kinds of living creatures of the land, the sea, and the sky (Genesis 1:20-25). Then, God said something unimaginably marvelous:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Genesis 1:26-27 (NIV) Then <strong>God said</strong>, "<strong>Let us</strong> make <strong>mankind in our image</strong>, in our likeness, so that they may <strong>rule over</strong> the fish in the sea and the birds in the sky, over the livestock and all the wild animals, and over all the creatures that move along the ground." So God created mankind in his own image, in the image of God he created them; <strong>male and female</strong> he created them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The only one true God said, "let us create men like us". What does that imply to diversity, equity, and diversity? Think about it, seriously.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="landscape" src="https://anqi-j.github.io/assets/images/DNA-spiral-52dde8d1a5dfc330b8f435724ad50145.jpg" width="1200" height="675" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>God created the uniqueness of every person. It is not to be discriminated, but to reflect the glory of God.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Psalm 139:13-14 (NIV) For <strong>you created my inmost being</strong>; you knit me together in my mother's womb. I praise you because I am <strong>fearfully and wonderfully made</strong>; your works are wonderful, I know that full well.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Jeremiah 1:5 (NIV) "Before I formed you in the womb <strong>I knew you</strong>, before you were born <strong>I set you apart</strong>; I appointed you as <strong>a prophet to the nations.</strong>"</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="christianity-teaches-the-command-of-inclusion">Christianity Teaches the Command of Inclusion<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#christianity-teaches-the-command-of-inclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Christianity Teaches the Command of Inclusion" title="Direct link to Christianity Teaches the Command of Inclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Every person who ever exists, is an image of God with infinite value and dignity inherited from God. Any person is infinitely more valuable than all the animals, the planets, and the stars. Hating a person is like hating God. Rejecting a person is like rejecting God. Stereotyping a person is like stereotyping God. Marginalizing a person is like marginalizing God. Torturing a person is like torturing God. Mocking a person is like mocking God. Murdering a person is like murdering God.</p>
<p>Christians are called to actively love everyone, no matter who they are, for God loves everyone:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>John 3:16 (NIV) For <strong>God so loved the world</strong> that he gave his one and only Son, that <strong>whoever believes in him</strong> shall not perish but have eternal life.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Matthew 22:36-40 (NIV) "Teacher, which is <strong>the greatest commandment in the Law</strong>?" Jesus replied: "'<strong>Love the Lord your God</strong> with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.' This is <strong>the first and greatest commandment</strong>. And <strong>the second is like it</strong>: '<strong>Love your neighbor as yourself.</strong>' All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments."</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Matthew 25:34-46 (NIV) "Then the King will say to those on his right, 'Come, you who are blessed by my Father; take your inheritance, the kingdom prepared for you since the creation of the world. For <strong>I was hungry and you gave me something to eat</strong>, <strong>I was thirsty and you gave me something to drink</strong>, <strong>I was a stranger and you invited me in</strong>, <strong>I needed clothes and you clothed me</strong>, <strong>I was sick and you looked after me</strong>, <strong>I was in prison and you came to visit me.</strong>' "Then the righteous will answer him, 'Lord, when did we see you hungry and feed you, or thirsty and give you something to drink? When did we see you a stranger and invite you in, or needing clothes and clothe you? When did we see you sick or in prison and go to visit you?' "The King will reply, 'Truly I tell you, <strong>whatever you did for one of the least of these brothers and sisters of mine, you did for me.</strong>' "Then he will say to those on his left, 'Depart from me, you who are cursed, into the eternal fire prepared for the devil and his angels. For I was hungry and you gave me nothing to eat, I was thirsty and you gave me nothing to drink, I was a stranger and you did not invite me in, I needed clothes and you did not clothe me, I was sick and in prison and you did not look after me.' "They also will answer, 'Lord, when did we see you hungry or thirsty or a stranger or needing clothes or sick or in prison, and did not help you?' "He will reply, 'Truly I tell you, <strong>whatever you did not do for one of the least of these, you did not do for me.</strong>' "Then they will go away to eternal punishment, but the righteous to eternal life."</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="christianity-teaches-the-equity-of-salvation">Christianity Teaches the Equity of Salvation<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#christianity-teaches-the-equity-of-salvation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Christianity Teaches the Equity of Salvation" title="Direct link to Christianity Teaches the Equity of Salvation">​</a></h2>
<p>For a Christian, salvation in the righteousness of God by the grace of God from the wrath of God to the presence of God, is the unparalleled, supreme and paramount purpose of life. <strong>To whom God offers salvation? All.</strong> Is all inclusive? Yes. Will all be diverse? Yes. Is salvation to all impartial? Yes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>John 11:25-26 (NIV) Jesus said to her, "I am the resurrection and the life. <strong>The one who believes in me</strong> will live, even though they die; and <strong>whoever lives by believing in me</strong> will never die. Do you believe this?"</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>1 John 2:2 (NIV) [Jesus] He is <strong>the atoning sacrifice</strong> for our sins, and not only for ours but also <strong>for the sins of the whole world.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>All nations:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Genesis 12:1-3 (NIV) The LORD had said to Abram, "<strong>Go from your country</strong>, your people and your father's household to the land I will show you. "<strong>I will make you into a great nation</strong>, and I will bless you; I will make your name great, and <strong>you will be a blessing</strong>. I will bless those who bless you, and whoever curses you I will curse; and <strong>all peoples on earth will be blessed through you.</strong>"</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Revelation 7:9-10 (NIV) After this I looked, and there before me was <strong>a great multitude</strong> that no one could count, <strong>from every nation, tribe, people and language</strong>, standing before the throne and before the Lamb. They were <strong>wearing white robes</strong> and were <strong>holding palm branches</strong> in their hands. And they cried out in a loud voice: "<strong>Salvation belongs to our God</strong>, who sits on the throne, and to the Lamb."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All races, all social statuses, all genders, all ages:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Galatians 3:26-29 (NIV) So <strong>in Christ Jesus</strong> you are all <strong>children of God</strong> through faith, for all of you who were baptized into Christ have <strong>clothed yourselves with Christ</strong>. There is <strong>neither Jew nor Gentile</strong>, <strong>neither slave nor free</strong>, <strong>nor is there male and female</strong>, for you are all one in Christ Jesus. If you belong to Christ, then you are Abraham's seed, and heirs according to the promise.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Acts 2:12-21 (NIV) No, this is what was spoken by <strong>the prophet Joel</strong>: "'In the last days, God says, <strong>I will pour out my Spirit on all people</strong>. Your <strong>sons and daughters</strong> will prophesy, your <strong>young men</strong> will see visions, <strong>your old men</strong> will dream dreams. Even on my servants, <strong>both men and women</strong>, I will pour out my Spirit in those days, and they will prophesy. I will show wonders in the heavens above and signs on the earth below, blood and fire and billows of smoke. The sun will be turned to darkness and the moon to blood before the coming of the great and glorious day of the Lord. And <strong>everyone who calls on the name of the Lord will be saved.</strong>'</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="square" src="https://anqi-j.github.io/assets/images/heart-nations-ca64dbe05689f396a1cbde4646f5444b.jpg" width="1200" height="1084" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>All sinners:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Matthew 9:10-13 (NIV) While Jesus was having dinner at Matthew's house, many <strong>tax collectors and sinners</strong> came and ate with him and his disciples. When the Pharisees saw this, they asked his disciples, "Why does your teacher eat with tax collectors and sinners?" On hearing this, Jesus said, "<strong>It is not the healthy who need a doctor, but the sick.</strong> But go and learn what this means: '<strong>I desire mercy, not sacrifice.</strong>' For <strong>I have not come to call the righteous, but sinners.</strong>"</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Romans 10:9-13 (NIV) If you declare with your mouth, "<strong>Jesus is Lord</strong>," and believe in your heart that <strong>God raised him from the dead</strong>, you <strong>will be saved</strong>. For it is with your heart that you believe and are justified, and it is with your mouth that you profess your faith and are saved. As Scripture says, "<strong>Anyone who believes in him will never be put to shame.</strong>" For there is <strong>no difference between Jew and Gentile</strong>—the same Lord is <strong>Lord of all</strong> and <strong>richly blesses all who call on him</strong>, for, "<strong>Everyone who calls on the name of the Lord will be saved.</strong>"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The last two statements show how Christianity is different from all other religions in how salvation is achieved. For all other religions, everyone is equally required to follow a set of moral codes and religious activities, if you want to be "saved" (a better current life, a better next life, etc.). You are your own savior if you do your things. For Christianity, <strong>everyone is equally and infinitely away from God</strong> (Romans 3:10-18). You will never save yourself no matter how well you follow whatever moral codes, and no matter how involved you attend religious activities and irreligious activities. At the same time, <strong>everyone is equally invited to an infinitely close relationship with God</strong>, for Him to travel an infinite distance to be with you and be within you, if you acknowledge God is your sole righteousness and Savior, the only possible salvation credited/gifted through your faith by His grace.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="landscape" src="https://anqi-j.github.io/assets/images/path-rainbow-a98607eb0212efc22e6d06e3b3defcc6.jpg" width="1200" height="736" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="christianity-teaches-exclusion">Christianity Teaches Exclusion<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#christianity-teaches-exclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Christianity Teaches Exclusion" title="Direct link to Christianity Teaches Exclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>If you have been following along the discussion, you may see a dangling modifier here and there--<strong>"Whoever believes in Jesus Christ"</strong>. What that means is, salvation is intended to all, but may not be extended to all. The extent of salvation is equal to the intent of salvation if and only if "Everyone believes in Jesus Christ." Sadly, that is false.</p>
<p>Does this contradict the diversity, equity, and inclusion Christianity has claimed? What about other religions? Isn't Christianity intolerant to claim some people will be eternally separated and excluded from God? To address the questions, I would like to bring two more concepts into our discussion: <strong>reality and choice.</strong></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reality-is-exclusive">Reality Is Exclusive<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#reality-is-exclusive" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reality Is Exclusive" title="Direct link to Reality Is Exclusive">​</a></h3>
<p>Reality is built upon truth. And truth is exclusive. If we believe there is one moon surrounding the Earth, then we don't believe there is no moon or more than one moon surrounding the Earth. If we believe George Washington was the first President of the United States, and the presidency is one person at a time, then we don't believe anyone else to be the first President of the United States.</p>
<p>Now, assume you plan to jump off a cliff. You think you will not die after, and I think you will die after. Only one of us can be right. Then who is right? I don't know; it depends on so many physical and biological parameters. What I know is that the reality will tell you, as first-hand experience, and only one of us can be right.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="portrait" src="https://anqi-j.github.io/assets/images/jump-cliff-64baaa2113b6a7d0b9eb3822db4434bf.jpg" width="1200" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reality is exclusive. Different religions are contradictory in their understanding of the fundamentals of reality. For example, Christianity claims that Jesus died on the cross and came back to life physically. His sacrifice justifies salvation. Islam claims that Jesus did not die on the cross and went to Heaven. The will of Allah distributes salvation. Judaism, Atheism and Hinduism claims that Jesus died on the cross and did not come back to life physically. We all know they cannot be all true. In fact, at most one of them can be true.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="choice-is-exclusive">Choice Is Exclusive<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#choice-is-exclusive" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Choice Is Exclusive" title="Direct link to Choice Is Exclusive">​</a></h3>
<p>Choice is "an act of selecting or making a decision when faced with two or more possibilities." By definition, it selects one possibility and excludes other possibilities. Let us dream about a romantic relationship:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A young man really likes a lady. He wants to be married to her and live happily together ever after. Then he reached out to talk to her. She ignored. He sent flowers to her. She took them and said nothing more. He wrote a long love letter from the deepest part of his heart, and invited her to consider a relationship. She threw the letter away and mocked his efforts. He asked his friends to talk with her and help her. She liked his friends and started to date his friends. But she still did not like him. One time he heard about she was heavily in debt, he paid in full with all his savings. She knew about it later, and shrugged it off. His heart was broken.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>After he tried everything possible, which of the following do you think he should do?</p>
<ol>
<li>Give up and leave her alone.</li>
<li>Kidnap her back home to be his wife.</li>
</ol>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="landscape" src="https://anqi-j.github.io/assets/images/hearts-love-41081ceec74b601494e6bcc24b66235d.jpg" width="1200" height="779" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><strong>Out of love, he should choose 1.</strong> That is the love of God to you. He is doing so many things to invite you, through creation, nature, coincidences, circumstances, dreams, voices, relationships, and particularly the Bible. God wants you to be with Him for eternity, but He does not want to force you to be with Him for eternity, because you are created in His image with infinite value and dignity. In short, <strong>God never wants you to be excluded, unless you choose to.</strong></p>
<p>Furthermore, God knows when He should give up and prepare you a place to be alone, because He knows you will no longer be responsive (Romans 1:28). But you don't know. You may think you are just "postponing" God to be Lord of your life, but you may be making the final choice to be independent from God and His goodness. It is like building a relationship; timing matters, and bravery is needed. As long as you are alive, God wants you to turn back to Him.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="back-to-diversity-equity-and-inclusion">Back to Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#back-to-diversity-equity-and-inclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Back to Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion" title="Direct link to Back to Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion">​</a></h3>
<p>Diversity, equity and inclusion have to be manifested in the light of the exclusiveness of the reality and our choices. That exclusiveness is a boundary that no one can go across.</p>
<p>Diversity of the salvation of God also means you can choose to be saved, or not to be saved. Love cannot be forced. If you do not make the choice, you are choosing not to be saved by default, because salvation is a relationship reconciled, and reconciliation requires the choice of both parties.</p>
<p>Equity of the salvation of God also means you are given the choice between God and not-God, just like everyone else. You have the freedom to accept the reality or to rebel against the reality. God is just and fair; He will give you what you deserve according to your choice and deeds, the same to everyone else (Romans 2:6).</p>
<p>Inclusion of the salvation of God also means you are always welcomed to be included, but you can only be truly included if you want to be included. If you prefer to be independent from God for all your life, why would He force you to be with Him forever and ever? <strong>If anyone does not respect the choice of another person, he is not inclusive, but coercive.</strong></p>
<p>If you would like to learn more about why believing in Jesus Christ is the only way to salvation, welcome to read <a href="https://www.mindinchrist.com/blog/foundational/salvationComesFromLord" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this article</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="landscape" src="https://anqi-j.github.io/assets/images/breath-water-cross-71c6d5a7f0333a6c190a1d3e7703ef43.jpg" width="1200" height="753" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="christianity-teaches-homogeneity">Christianity Teaches Homogeneity<a href="https://anqi-j.github.io/blog/ChristianityDiversityEquityInclusion#christianity-teaches-homogeneity" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Christianity Teaches Homogeneity" title="Direct link to Christianity Teaches Homogeneity">​</a></h2>
<p>The value of diversity is not innate. It derives from the diversity of the goodness of God. The diversity of diseases, sufferings, and evil is not desired. Imagine you can choose which neighbors to live with you forever, would you prefer this diverse group?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Romans 1:29-32 (NIV) They have become filled with every kind of <strong>wickedness, evil, greed and depravity</strong>. They are <strong>full of envy, murder, strife, deceit and malice</strong>. They are <strong>gossips, slanderers, God-haters, insolent, arrogant and boastful</strong>; they <strong>invent ways of doing evil</strong>; they <strong>disobey their parents</strong>; they <strong>have no understanding, no fidelity, no love, no mercy</strong>. Although they know God's righteous decree that those who do such things deserve death, they not only continue to do these very things but also approve of those who practice them.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Galatians 5:19-21 (NIV) The acts of the flesh are obvious: <strong>sexual immorality, impurity and debauchery; idolatry and witchcraft; hatred, discord, jealousy, fits of rage, selfish ambition, dissensions, factions and envy; drunkenness, orgies, and the like</strong>. I warn you, as I did before, that those who live like this will not inherit the kingdom of God.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>1 Corinthians 6:9-10 (NIV) Or do you not know that wrongdoers will not inherit the kingdom of God? Do not be deceived: Neither <strong>the sexually immoral</strong> nor <strong>idolaters</strong> nor <strong>adulterers</strong> nor <strong>men who have sex with men</strong> nor <strong>thieves</strong> nor <strong>the greedy</strong> nor <strong>drunkards</strong> nor <strong>slanderers</strong> nor <strong>swindlers</strong> will inherit the kingdom of God.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Revelation 21:8(NIV) But <strong>the cowardly</strong>, <strong>the unbelieving</strong>, <strong>the vile</strong>, <strong>the murderers</strong>, <strong>the sexually immoral</strong>, those who <strong>practice magic arts</strong>, <strong>the idolaters</strong> and <strong>all liars</strong>--they will be consigned to the fiery lake of burning sulfur. This is the second death."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>God has said the Heaven is homogeneous. Whoever and only who is righteous will enter His Kingdom. It will be perfect without death, tears, and pain.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Matthew 13:47-50 (NIV) "Once again, <strong>the kingdom of heaven</strong> is like a net that was let down into the lake and caught all kinds of fish. When it was full, the fishermen pulled it up on the shore. Then they sat down and <strong>collected the good fish in baskets, but threw the bad away.</strong> This is how it will be at the end of the age. The angels will come and <strong>separate the wicked from the righteous</strong> and throw them into the blazing furnace, where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Revelation 21:4 (NIV) 'He will wipe every tear from their eyes. There will be no more death' or mourning or crying or pain, for <strong>the old order of things has passed away.</strong>"</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="landscape" src="https://anqi-j.github.io/assets/images/earth-shine-0ce0f0cc1456aea322fcdaa4d7df40b7.jpg" width="1200" height="473" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>You may not be able to imagine and plan the logistics God needs to realize before this could ever happen. <strong>No worries, God has done it all.</strong> I list the major considerations below, and please check out the Bible and ask God to explain His plan to you.</p>
<ul>
<li>Reliability: How do I know God is loving? How do I know God is trustworthy? How do I know the Bible is His word? How do I know Jesus died for me? How do I know God makes room in Heaven and hell? How do I know I cannot go to Heaven by myself? <strong>If you are honest with yourself not being hostile to God, these questions are waiting for you to research and ponder.</strong> For example, the death and resurrection of Jesus Christ is a falsifiable historical claim that you can examine with direct and indirect evidence.</li>
<li>Justice: Why would God not let everyone in to Heaven? Why would God not punish the evil people in the history and in my life? How would God allow anyone in Heaven if you said all are sinners? How can God be just if He does not punish me, or you? <strong>God is both loving and just.</strong> He demands the punishments of our sins, and He is willing to be punished in your place--through the Son of God Jesus Christ.</li>
<li>Freedom: How could a good God lock me in a suffering place? Why would God take the freedom of eternity from people? Isn't He a persecuting tyrant? God is so good and loving, that He is willing to respect your choice and grant your desire to live in hell, a place without a relationship with God. <strong>Freedom is only about the choice, not the consequences.</strong> You can choose to jump into lava, but you cannot choose not to be burnt.</li>
<li>Forgiveness: Why would God forgive the horrible things I have done in my life? Why would God include me to His perfect place? Why would Jesus choose to die for me? Why I should not curse myself and die? The Bible says, "<strong>There is now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus</strong>, because through Christ Jesus the law of the Spirit who gives life has set you free from the law of sin and death." You will not be condemned, especially by yourself, if you choose to live in Christ Jesus.</li>
<li>Perfection: How could God sustain a perfect place to live if no one is perfect? Why would the next world not just be the same as this world? Why would God create men to pollute this world? <strong>The Spirit of God will respond and realize our choice of surrendering our life to God and give us new and eternal life for His glory.</strong> That is the good consequence of our choice of faith. He will transform our hearts and give us new desires that can never be obtained by human means. God makes us perfect if we rely on His perfectness.</li>
<li>Joy: Why would I choose to live in a place without fun for eternity? How could I not be bored after a certain time? What if I run out of interests and hobbies when living forever? <strong>Human are created to have God as our highest joy. Nothing else can satisfy our unquenchable thirst for joy.</strong> God is infinite, so your joy can also be infinite. Joy depends on desires. If what you desire is realized, you will be full of joy. God transforms us into new creation who desire Him and worship Him supernaturally naturally.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mranqizhang@gmail.com (Anqi Zhang)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>